BELDINE MOTURI

Software Engineer

(+254) 710206707 Nairobi, Kenya <u>beldinemoturi@gmail.com</u> <u>Linkedin</u> <u>Github</u>

Software engineer with 1 year project-based learning experience at ALX Africa Software Engineering program. Proven knowledge and interest in managing projects that create social impact after working in an international NGO for 2 years. Looking to contribute my skill set and experience to a company providing social impact.

SKILLS/TECHNOLOGIES

Languages:Frameworks:Tools:Python3FlaskMySQLC/C++Flask-SQLAlchemyRedisJavascript/TypescriptJQuery, AJAXMongoDBHTML/CSSBootstrapVersion control-Git

SQL

Soft skills: Teamwork and problem-solving, People management and Leadership, Time management, Adaptability, Project management.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Vote-App (Github link) - an online voting system

- Built an web application that digitizes a voting system, whilst ensuring user privacy and having security to ensure that free and fair elections are conducted. The app registers voters through admin accounts, authenticates them when they try logging in, gives access to candidates list for voting and maintains a structured database of voters and candidates information to ensure voting integrity.
- Using Python, Flask, MySQL and Javascript JQuery to create logic for registration, authentication, login and voting features.
- Solves the issue of having a digital voting system that is reliable, efficient all while maintaining user data privacy and security.

Creatives Connect (Github link) - a linkedin-like platform but for creatives.

- Built a web app that serves as a one-stop shop for creatives. The app provides functionality for users to create accounts, upload their portfolio and display skills, search and filter through projects/jobs and other creatives based on skills and location.
- Using Python, Javascript(Jquery) and SQL to dynamically display, store and create logic
- Solves the issue of creatives having a platform to easily find work/collaborate and for companies/individuals to easily search and find creatives to work on their projects

Airbnb Clone (Github link) - a clone of the Airbnb website

- Built a complete web application, integrating MySQL database storage, a back-end API, and front-end interface as a simple mimic of the Airbnb website.
- Using Flask, Flask-CORS and Flask-Blueprints to create a RESTful API for the app.
- Implemented a search feature using JQuery to dynamically display content on the front end

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intern Associate Consultant - Aludo Group

April 2022 - September 2022

- Reduced time spent on preparation for engagements by 50% by conducting market research, preparing and consolidating presentations, weekly management and project status reports
- Established an efficient document database during my first 30 days in Aludo Group, reducing slack time by 10% and improving overall
 efficiency.
- Provided administrative support to the CEO by responding to correspondence, organizing meetings and travel logistics and coordinating with the client project manager per project brief therefore improving his productivity.

Lead Business Developer - AIESEC in UoN

February 2020 - January 2021

- Expanded the organization's exchange Internship program client base with 4 new companies by conducting research and market segmentation, responding to a high volume of calls and emails from potential company partners.
- Implemented a framework for remote internships during the COVID-19 pandemic, which helped retain 80% of previous partner companies
- Led, successfully trained and managed a team of 3 new Business Developers who later developed connections with at least 2 companies each, therefore expanding the client base.

Partnership Developer - AIESEC in UoN

February 2019 - January 2020

- Negotiated favorable terms for partnerships and speakers during events, increasing the organization's partner base with 4 new companies and improving the quality of sessions at the events.
- Coordinated planning of the AIESEC in UoN annual CSR initiative, directly increasing donations to provide a network of 8 schools in Mathare with resources to buy essential hygiene products by 25%.
- Launched a framework for matching, training and tracking accountability partners for our exchange volunteers, which improved our exchange experience by ensuring a 50% increase in members that served as accountability partners during this year.

EDUCATION

University of Nairobi, Kenya (Graduating September 2023) - Bachelors in Economics and Statistics

February 2018 - September 2023

Relevant coursework: Microeconomics, Macroeconomics, Probability and Statistics, Data Analysis

ALX-Africa, Nairobi, Kenya – Certificate in Software Engineering

August 2021 - October 2022

Relevant coursework: Low- level programming(C/C++), High-level programming(Python, Javascript), System Engineering and DevOps, Databases(MySQL, Redis, MongoDB), Back-end Engineering specialization.

ZAKA Al Ready Academy – Certificate in Artificial Intelligence

November 2020 - March 2021

Relevant coursework: Azure platform fundamentals, Foundations of Data Science, Azure Data, AI fundamentals

Achievements: Won 2nd place during the hackathon at the end of the program by prototyping a chatbot solution for online gaming. The requirements were to provide a solution to a real life problem, using Machine Learning/AI and tools learned in the course of the program. Solutions were judged based on Innovation & creativity, potential impact, correctness and soundness of the solution and working prototype.